Now that we've thoroughly planned this out, go ahead and
では 計画が完了したので アプリの中に
build out this layout in your app.
レイアウトしていきましょう
You'll need to find and modify the activity_main.xml file.
activity_main.xml ファイルを見つけて 変更していかなければなりません
The activity_main.xml file should already be
activity_main.xml ファイルは プロジェクトを最初に作る時
open when you first create your project.
既に開かれているはずです
If it's not already open, you can find this file under the layout folder.
もし 開かれていないなら アプリ内の全てのファイルリストの
Under res under app in the project view of your app,
プロジェクトビューの中にある app の中の res フォルダの中
which lists all the files in your app.
layout フォルダの中にあります
The design pane is open by default, where you can drag and
デザインペインは初期設定の段階で すでに開いています
drop widgets from this palette here over onto the app.
パレットからウィジェットを持ってきて ドラッグ＆ドロップすることができます
However, I want you to use the text pane so you can write your XML here.
しかし ここではテキストペインを使って XML をここに書いてください
At any point, when you modify your XML, you can always select this content and
XML を変更する時は いつでも このコンテントを選択して変えることが
reformat it.
できます
Across the top of Android Studio you should see a bunch of menu items.
Android Studio 上部にはいくつもの メニューアイテムが表示されています
Click on Code, and then you'll find an option to Reformat Code.
「 Code 」をクリックすると 「 Reformat Code 」の選択肢があります
And here's the keyboard shortcut if you're on Mac.
これは Mac の場合の ショートカットキーです
You can reformat the code and selected text is fine.
Reformat codeを使用するに selected text で大丈夫です
Just click Run and
Run をクリックします
then it automatically reformats your code to fix the spacing and the tabs.
すると スペースやタブが修正された コードが自動的に変更されました
You can also select Rearrange Code.
Rearrange Code も選択できます
It modifies the order of the attributes here so that it's in the preferred order
これは Android の コードスタイルガイドラインに沿うように
according to the Android code style guidelines.
属性の順序を変えるものです
And now the code is a lot easier to read in this format.
フォーマット内のコードが とても読みやすくなりました
If you want a preview of what this code looks like,
もし コードがどんな見た目になるか プレビューが見たいなら
you can click on the Preview button here.
この「 Preview 」ボタンを クリックします
And this shows what it would look like on a device.
すると デバイス上の見え方が表示されます
But this isn't a substitute for running it on your device, so
しかし これはデバイスで実行した 代わりとはなりませんので
you should always run it on your device periodically.
いつも定期的に デバイス上で実行してください
Once you build out this layout, please also assign a view ID name
このレイアウトが完了したら 「０」と表示されている
on this second TextView here that displays a 0.
2番目のテキストビューに ビュー ID ネームを設定してください
Give it a view ID name of @+id/quantity_text_view.
ビュー ID ネームは 「 @+id/quantity_text_view 」としましょう
Use this exact name so that it will match our code later on.
後で私たちのコードにマッチさせるので このネームを間違いなく使ってください
Remember that we learned how to assign IDs to views in lesson one.
ID をビューに入れる方法は レッスン１で行いました
This example was for relative layout, where we had a dinner party for
親友とフレネミーたちへの ディナーパーティーに向けた
our best friends and our frenemies.
相対レイアウトの例でした
Also, the reason why we give this view an ID but
また このビューに ID を１つだけ入れる理由は
not the others is because we will want to later refer to this TextView so
後でこのテキストビューを 参照したいからです
that we can update it to increase or decrease the quantity.
そうすれば 数量の増減を更新できます
For styling the views, there's a couple small changes.
ビューのスタイリングでは 数か所にわずかな変更をします
This TextView here should have a text size of 16sp and use a black font color.
このテキストビューはフォントが 黒色の 16 sp サイズになるべきです
You can use the black system font color like we showed you in lesson one or
レッスン１でお見せしたように 黒のシステムフォントを使っても良いですし
you can use the black hex color, which we've included below.
私たちが下に加えた ブラック16進数カラーを使っても良いです
There's also 16 dp of space in between each of these views.
それぞれのビューの間には 16 dp のスペースを入れます
I know that this is the first time that you are going to be adding a button to
これが　XML レイアウトに行って ボタンを追加することになる
your XML layout.
最初の機会ですね
This is a really great opportunity for you to practice your Google search
これは ボタンをレイアウトに 追加する方法を見つけ出すために
skills in order to figure out how to add a button to your layout.
あなたが Google 検索技術を 練習する本当に良い機会です
If you really get stuck, you can check the hint in the instructor notes.
もし 完全に行きづまったら インストラクターノートのヒントをどうぞ
As you build this up,
これを作っている時は
periodically run the app on your device to check that it's working as expected.
予想通りに動くかチェックのために 定期的にデバイス上でアプリを実行して下さい
When you're done with all of this, answer this question.
全て終えたなら この質問に答えて下さい
What happens when you click on this button?
このボタンを押したら何が起こりますか？